Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Video Editing
Gigglebot
fedew
Timing
Gab
Quality Control
Galaxy 9000
Pepperjack
PhosCity
Scolines
Zenef
Galaxy 9000
Pepperjack
PhosCity
Scolines
Zenef
Soundtracking
Halee
Graphics
Datenshi
Inherited will...
Karaoke
KaitouYahiko
the tides of time,
and humanity's dreams...
Subtitle Editing
Gordingus
Lil T
Pollychan
Westfal
Gordingus
Lil T
Pollychan
Westfal
They cannot be stopped.
Translation
Funimation
PamkinPinguin
Raws
Neo-Raws
As long as people seek freedom,
these things will never cease to be.
shin
shin
eve
in
shin
stuck
stuck
TIKKU
TIKKU
dr
ama
TIKKU
land!
land!
you,
you,
ka
ra
you,
land!
land!
Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Straw Hat Luffy...
What a fitting end to your story...
Croc-ish
{Within six minutes or so, this yard will
be blown up along with the Square.-OG}In about six minutes, this yard
will explode along with the square.
Apologies, but I'm on a tight schedule.
You just sit back
and celebrate the coronation...
{and celebrate the birth
of a new king of the sand country.-OG}of the Kingdom of Sand's new ruler.
Well, then...
I should also be on my way.
{He said it's in the mortuary
temple to the west of here...-OG}He said the mortuary temple
is west of here...
You missed...
That was close!
I thought I was a goner!
That jerk... He's gone now...
I saw him flying that way!
I won't let him get away!
That damn croc!
Mortuary Temple
(Royal Mausoleum)
West of the Palace
Mortuary Temple
(Royal Mausoleum)
West of the Palace
Mortuary Temple
(Royal Mausoleum)
West of the Palace
So this is the royal mausoleum...
{where the bodies
of generations of kings sleep...-OG}the final resting place
for generations of kings.
Where's the poneglyph?
A hidden passage!
The poneglyph lies deep underground.
{Normally, people aren't even aware
of poneglyphs' existence...-OG}Most people aren't even aware
of the poneglyphs' existence.
{What's happening behind
the scenes is deep.-OG}The criminal underworld is vast.{she's saying the underworld (like the shady part of the world) is deep (vast), so even tho he is a king of the world government, that doesn't mean he'd know everything about it-TL from PP}
{Even if countries belong to the World Government, it doesn't mean their kings know everything.-OG}Even the kings under
the World Government don't know everything.
Don't beat yourself up.
{since you probably didn't know
there was someone in this world who can decipher them.-OG}You probably didn't know there was
someone out there who could read them.
You can read poneglyphs?
Yes...
That's why Crocodile and I teamed up.
Because of that,
I'm indispensable to him.
{It's likely that the poneglyph
in this country tells where Pluton is.-OG}It's likely that the poneglyph in this country
has the location of Pluton inscribed on it.
Am I right?
I have no idea.
{Arabasta's royal family has been
obligated for generations to protect it.-OG}Arabasta's royal family has been tasked
with protecting it for generations.
That's all it is to us.
Protecting it?
Don't make me laugh!
Quite impressive...
It rests beyond the doors at the end.
Indeed...
You vermin...
What's wrong with you?!
{What am I doing?! I'm trying to put
myself in Crocodile's shoes!-OG}What?! I'm trying to put
myself in Crocodile's shoes!
{Like, if I were him, where would I
shoot a cannon from...?-OG}Like, "Where would I
shoot a cannon from?!"
{Forget it! Just look for the cannoneer!
We've got less than five minutes!-OG}Well, stop! We've got
five minutes to find it!
{Five more minutes! A million lives
will be blown up in five minutes!-OG}Five minutes! A million lives
will be lost in five more minutes!
{We gotta hurry...! We gotta hurry up
and find the cannoneer!-OG}We've gotta hurry...! We've gotta
hurry up and find the cannoneer!
{Chopper! Can't you find
the guy by using your nose?-OH}Chopper! Can't you just
sniff this guy out?!
{I can't. The smell of gunpowder
is all over the town!-OG}{No can do! The only thing
I can smell is all this gunpowder-WF}I'm sorry, but all I can smell
right now is gunpowder!
Then... listen!
{Find the smell of "a cannoneer who may be
aiming at the center of the Square."-OG}Can you sniff out "a guy who's
aiming a cannon at the square"?
How does that smell?!
How should I know?! Just try!
What?!
{A cannonball that can blow up
a 5 km diameter...-OG}It can level a five-kilometer area...
Wait! Then it's gotta be pretty big...
{If it is to be shot from a cannon,
it won't travel very far...-OG}And if it's being fired from
a cannon, it can't go very far...
{Then it should be closer
to the square after all?!-OG}Then it's closer to
the square after all?!
I don't have time to go around!
I'm making a shortcut!
Find anything, Pell?!
{I searched every corner of the rooftops
of the buildings near the Square, but I saw no preparations
for the cannon anywhere.-OG}I checked every rooftop near the square,
but there were no signs of a cannon!
{Then... it might be from
somewhere inside a building...-OG}Then... maybe it's inside
one of these buildings...!
I'll search every last one!
All right!
{How many times do you have to come
at me before you're satisfied?-OG}What's it going to take
for you to just stay down?!
Crocodile...
{Looks like you were taken
down by that woman...-OG}Looks like you were
no match for her...
{I never thought that you'd follow
me to this town... Marines...-OG}I'm surprised the Marines
followed me all the way here.
Where's your boss?
Did that smoke bastard run away?
Losers shouldn't preach about justice.
This sea is for the mighty.
{Go back to your base and just devote
your time to talking about justice.-OG}If you want to prattle on about justice,
do it from the safety of your base.
Crocodile!
Straw Hat!
Where did... that damn croc go?!
Tell me!
Where's that croc?!
{He went in the direction
of the mortuary temple.-OG}He's headed toward
the mortuary temple.
That way?! Thanks!
What justice...?
To hell with Marine Headquarters...!{I think she’s self-deprecating, because she represents “Marine Headquarters” and she makes it seem like a joke, this feels like she is upset at the Marine Headquarters instead-TL from PP}
Oh?
I'm having trouble moving...
That's weird... I ate plenty of meat...
{What's wrong...?
These are such small wounds...-OG}What's wrong?
It's just some scratches...
Maybe... I'm a little tired...
{Did you find what
you were looking for?-WF}Did it tell you what
you wanted to know?
Ah, there we are...
A hidden staircase.
Four... Four more minutes...!
Aren't there more?
This country isn't hiding any others?
Are you not satisfied?
I did as you asked.
That you did...
{Just as you'd expect
from a national secret...-OG}Now this is what you call
a national secret...
{No matter how
desperately you search, it can't be found unless
you know where it is.-OG}Try as you might, you'd never find it
without knowledge of its location.
{So this is the poneglyph,
huh, Nico Robin?-OG}So, Nico Robin...
this is the poneglyph?
That didn't take long.
It's strange, huh...?{i think he is saying it feels weird that it took that fast, or that it's done now, like "feel's weird, i dunno..."-TL from PP}
Were you able to decipher it?
Yes.
Good. Now, read
the so-called poneglyph...
In the empyreal year 239...
Kahire conquered Arabasta.
{In 260, Tamer ruled
the Bytine dynasty.-OG}In the year 260, Tamer
of the Bytine dynasty ruled.
In 306, the Taf Cathedral
was completed in Erumalu.
In 325, the hero Mamudine of Oltair–
Hey, quit screwing around!
You think that's what
we've been looking for?!
{Who cares about the history
of this country?!-OG}Who cares about
this country's history?!
{Just tell me the location of the world's most disastrous "military power"
that is sleeping in this country!-OG}Tell me where I can find the world's
most destructive military power!
Where is Pluton?!
It doesn't say.
Huh?!
The only thing recorded
here is history.
What?!
Pluton...
{I didn't see that word
mentioned even once.-OG}That name isn't mentioned here once.
Well...
I see...
What a pity.
{You've been an excellent
partner to me, but...-OG}You've been an exceptional partner, but...
you've outlived your usefulness.
What...?!
{The agreement that we made four
years ago has been achieved here.-OG}{Our arrangement from four
years ago has reached its conclusion.-WF}The terms of our agreement from
four years ago have just been met.
Back then, you came
to me with a promise...
{If I take you to where
the Poneglyph is,-OG}that if I could get you
to the poneglyph,
{you'd turn over the information
on the weapon to me...-OG}{I'll tell you everything
it says about the weapon."-WF}{you'd tell me everything
it said about the weapon.-WF}you'd tell me all I need
to know about the weapon.
{Over the last four years,
Baroque Works benefited greatly-WF+Polly}In terms of both
intellect and leadership,
your work these past
four years has been superb.
At least in those regards...
you managed to be useful to me.
But...
you couldn't keep up
your end of the bargain!
{The poneglyph in this country doesn't
even show a clue on the Pluton.-OG}This poneglyph holds no
information concerning Pluton!
Or...
{is it that you weren't planning
to tell me from the start, even if you found out?-OG}{could it be regardless
of what you discovered, you never intended on telling me?-WF}maybe you never intended to tell me,
regardless of what you found?
Even so...
I harbor no grudge against you.
Do you know why, Nico Robin?
{How silly... We were
a team for four years.-OG}Ridiculous... We've been
partners for four years!
Of course you'd pull
something like this!
Water?!
{If you get wet, a knife
can stick in you, right?!-OG}I can stab you once
you're wet, right?!
He dodged it! Where'd he–
{I'll forgive you for everything,
Nico Robin...-OG}I forgive you for everything,
Nico Robin...
After all...
from the very beginning...
I never trusted anyone.
{I now know from Cobra's reaction
that Pluton really exists.-OG}Cobra's reaction confirmed
Pluton's existence to me.
{I don't have to depend on
the poneglyph. I'll find it on my own.-OG}I'll find it on my own.
I no longer need the poneglyph.
{Once this country becomes mine,
it's just a matter of time.-OG}Once this country is mine,
it's only a matter of time.
{What's going on?! It's still too early
for the attack on the Square!-OG}What's happening? It's too soon
for the attack on the square!
You... What did you do?
{Well... nothing major... This
underground sacred temple is built-OG}Oh, nothing major. This tomb
is built in such a way
{so that pulling just one small column
out will cause the entire balance-OG}that removing one small column
destabilizes the structure,
{to be disrupted
and destroy the temple.-OG}destroying the entire temple.
You two... will perish here with me.
{As the twelfth king
of the Nefertari Family,-OG}As the twelfth king
of the Nefertari dynasty,
{I can't give this sand kingdom
to someone like you.-OG}I cannot allow someone like you
to seize the Kingdom of Sand.
Outstanding... An example
for kings everywhere!
{Are you trying to be buried alive,
taking me with you for the country?!-OG}You're willing to die down here
with me to protect your country?
Unfortunately... you can't kill me.
{I can change all the bedrocks
into sand and escape from here.-OG}I'll simply change the bedrock
to sand and make my escape.
Your death will be for naught, Cobra.
There's less than
three minutes remaining.
{With the collapse of this sacred temple
and the big explosion of the Square,-OG}When the temple collapses
and the square blows up,
{everyone in my way
will be blown up in an instant!-OG}all my obstacles
will vanish in an instant!
In that moment, this land...
will become my country!
Where is it?
Only three more minutes...
{A cannon big enough
to blow up a 5 km diameter...-OG}A cannon with
a five-kilometer blast area…
There can't be many places
where such a thing would fit...
{Why can't we find it when
we search this much...?-OG}We're searching so hard,
so why can't we find it...?!
An open space where
a big cannon can fit...
A stray bullet!
An open space...
Hey, no fair, Koza! You were
hiding in a place like this?!
Leader! No fair!
That's it...!
That place can...
Watch where you're aiming, jerk!
Smoke Star!
{It doesn't attract people's
attention and it's a big space.-OG}It's unassuming while
providing plenty of space.
I'm not with the Rebel Army!
Usopp Hammer!
Usopp's Rubber Band of Doom!
Learn your lesson, bastard?
Man, who do they think I am...?!
{Don't be surprised when I tell
you this. No, be surprised!-OG}Don't be shocked by this!
Actually, be shocked!
I am the famous Captain–
What? O-Oh, it's you, Vivi.
Did you find the cannoneer?
I figured it out! I know where it is!
What?! Really?!
Okay, then! I'll signal them!
{In any case, I'll call everyone!
You're sure about it, right?-OG}This should get their attention!
You're sure, right?!
Lethal...
Red Serpent Star!
Man, I slept like a baby.
Huh...? Oh, that's right.
{My body suddenly became
incapable of moving...-OG}I couldn't move all of a sudden...
{so I decided to risk it and take
a nap since it couldn't be helped.-OG}so I figured a nap wouldn't hurt.
And now I feel better, so...
Oh, yeah!
I'm gonna beat
the crap outta that croc!
That hole...
looks croc-ish...!
What's with this place?
It's falling apart!
There's no mistake!
{The cannoneer must be in there!
I finally figured it out!-OG}The cannoneer has to be there!
I finally figured it out!
Are you sure it's there, Vivi?!
If this storm is part of his plan...
{it has to be somewhere they
could still hit the target from...!-WF}it should be a place where
they can still hit the target...
{And it also has to be an open space
where a large cannon can fit-OG}It also has to be large enough
to house the cannon
while being hidden from the sky!
{Look! This place is
unexpectedly large, isn't it?-OG}Look! This place is pretty big, right?!
{Why don't we make
this place our secret base?-OG}Why don't we make it
our secret base?
– Yeah!
It's the only place I can think of!
{Okay! Hold on! Everyone's headed
here. So we'll leave a message...-OG}Then give me a second! Everyone's
on their way, so I'll leave a message...
I'm gonna go on ahead, Usopp!
What?! W-Wait, Vivi! W-Wait!
Hurry!
Oh, okay.
Alright, we found her!
It's the princess!
That signal led us right to her!
{There're still some members
of Baroque Works...!-OG}More Baroque Works operatives...?!
I led the bad guys right to us!
That's Usopp's signal.
But why is the palace so far away?!
Good, it's close!
I wonder if they found the cannoneer.
They must have! Hurry!
Usopp...
Noise...!
So this is... This is my...
Now! Let's go, Vivi!
Okay!
Th-They ran away!
Stop right there!
You...!
I've got you now, you damn croc!
How are you still alive?!
{No matter how many times I kill you,
why do you stand up to me?!-OG}{Why do you keep coming back,
no matter how many times I kill you?!-WF}I kill you and I kill you, so why
do you continue to stand against me?!
Well?! Straw Hat!
{How... did he survive
and come here...?-OG}{How in the world... did he
survive and find this place...?-WF}Why is he here? So he was still alive?
Just who is this young man...?
Straw Hat...
{Just how many times
do you want to be killed?-OG}How many times
do I have to kill you?!
You still haven't given back...
what you took!
What I took?!
Do you mean money?
Fame?
Trust?
Lives?
Rain?!
What exactly do you
want me to return?!
{There're so many things
that I took away.-OG}I've lost track of all
the things I've taken!
This country!
This country?
You say the damnedest things.
{I'm just about to take this country...
by becoming its king.-OG}{This country will be mine shortly...
I shall become its new king!-WF}This country is about to be mine...
I shall become its new king!
{When we got to this island,
it was already gone.-OG}When we got here,
it was already long gone.
Her country...!
{I'm going to persuade
the Rebel Army...-OG}I have to reason
with the Rebel Army...
{because I want no more
shedding of blood!-OG}because I want this bloodshed
to finally come to an end!
Not long ago, this city
was a verdant paradise.
Please, Vivi!
You have to stop those fools!
If this is really her country...
What's wrong...
with not wanting people to die?!
Just one look at this kingdom
and even I can tell...
what needs to be done!
Do you think it's enough
to risk your life alone?!
I've got–
I-I've got nothing else to give...
Why don't you try risking
all of our lives together?!
Aren't we friends?!
If this really is her country...
she should be...
smiling more!
{Even if you talk cool, when you don't
have water with you, what can you...-OG}Big talk, but without any water,
you can't even land a single–
It can't be...
He kicked me without
using any water...
If only you hadn't come
to this country...
Arabasta would've remained peaceful!
Isn't it just heartrending?
Love for this country is what
will lead to its destruction.
Crocodile!
Wai–
Could it be... you're using...
your own blood...?
{Sand can be hardened
by blood, too, can't it?-OG}Blood can harden sand too, right?
From Rainbase... to the palace...
{and to the underground
mortuary temple...-OG}all the way to the mortuary temple...
{I'll reward you for your
persistence in challenging me,-OG}Since you climbed your way
out of hell twice to challenge me,
I'll reward your persistence...
You bastard...!
...like a pirate!
{It seems that you want
to beat me up no matter what.-OG}It seems you'll stop
at nothing to take me down.
{And I'll also admit that you're
an annoying enemy to me.-OG}I have to admit, you've become
a real thorn in my side.
It came off!
What the...?
It's a venomous hook.
That right?
{As a competent enough pirate,
you seem to understand...-OG}If you're the real deal,
you should know...
{that a duel between pirates
is always a fight for survival,-OG}that a duel between pirates
is a fight to the death.
{and that there's no such
thing as "playing dirty."-OG}There's no such thing
as "fighting dirty."
{When the explosion happens up there, this place will probably collapse
in one breath as well.-OG}When the square explodes,
this tomb will collapse as well.
This is the last time...
This ends right here, right now!
The smoke was in
that direction, right?
No, was it this way?
What?! Marines?!
Look! It's Roronoa Zoro!
{Dammit! I didn't realize that
the Marines showed up in this town...-OG}Dammit! I didn't realize the Marines
were running around here, too...!
There's no time to spare...
Guess I've gotta fight!
I'll settle this in three seconds!
{You...! Why are you
in a place like this?!-OG}You...! Why are you here?!
What are you doing?!
Hey, that's my line!
Roronoa Zoro!
{Go back! If you go north at the last
corner, you can get to the square!-OG}Back the way you came, north from
the last corner is the square!
Go back and turn right! Not this way!
Are you stupid?!
Stupid?!
Hurry up!
Go!
Wh-What?!
What's going on?!
Wait! Hold it!
Th-Tha... Thank...
We'll cover you!
{Please stop the explosion
of the Square. Now, hurry!-OG}Please, stop the bombing
of the square! Now, hurry!
Thank you! Hurry, Usopp!
Uh... Right!
Hurry! Hurry!
We lost a lot of time!
{I don't know why they did,
but if the Marines hadn't helped,-OG}I don't know why the Marines
helped us, but if they hadn't,
it would've been a lot worse!
Focus, dummy!
{If the attack isn't stopped,
the casualties will be a lot worse!-OG}If we don't stop this attack,
way more people will die!
Right!
{The attack can't be
stopped by praying!-OG}{We won't solve anything
by sitting around and praying!-WF}Prayers aren't what'll stop this attack!
{In two minutes, are we gonna be
winners or dead bodies...?-OG}We have two minutes! It's do or die!
We still have a minute and a half!
Yes...!
You've got us!
Yes!
There they are!
Vivi! Usopp!
Nami! Tony!
What's going on?!
The Marines helped us!
Did you find the cannoneer?!
{We haven't confirmed it yet,
but there's no mistake!-OG}We don't have confirmation,
but I'm positive!
{I must've looked at it many times,
but it was my blind spot.-OG}I looked at it so many times
but never considered it!
{The cannoneer is over there
without a doubt!-OG}The cannoneer is up there,
no doubt about it!
What?!
The clock tower...
I see!
{From that place, he can get
a good shot at the Square!-OG}They'd have a great
shot from up there!
{If only Pell would get here,
we could stop the attack.-OG}If only Pell was here,
we could put a stop to this...!
Pell...!
We're running out of time!
{If I'm not mistaken, the smoke
rose around here, but...-OG}If I'm not mistaken, the smoke
was rising from here, but...
Ribbit, ribbit, ribbit, ribbit...
Hey, listen.
{I just shot down a big bird
using this ribbit-ribbit gun.-OG}I just nailed one hell of a bird
with my Ribbit-Ribbit Gun!
I was careless...!
Gum-Gum Pisto–
Who in the world is he...?
{Crocodile treated even our kingdom's
proud warriors like worms, and yet...-OG}Crocodile crushed our mightiest
warriors like mere insects, and yet...
{You were skewered...
buried alive... and dried up...-OG}I skewered you, buried you alive,
and even mummified you...
{Even you, who stood
back up after all that...-OG}but even you, who stood
back up after all that...
won't be able to survive this.
{Game over...The poison will pass
into your system soon.-OG}Our game is at an end. That venom
will soon spread throughout your body.
You just don't get it!
I wonder what happened...
I don't see Pell anywhere...
Hey, Vivi.
{We can't go up that high
within a minute all by ourselves!-OG}We can't get all the way up there
in a minute! Not by ourselves!
Pell! Where are you?! Hurry!
At this point, we have to try!
{We have no choice but to use
the stairs! Where's the entrance–-OG}We'll take the stairs! Here's the entra–
Hey!
– Huh?!
Nami, my sweet! Vivi, my love!
What are you doing up there?!
What do you mean?!
You left a message under
the smoke, didn't you?!
{It said "clock tower."
That's why I came up here.-OG}It said "clock tower,"
so I came up here.
What should I do?
Where's the cannoneer?
He's at the top! The top!
Go up there and kick some ass!
Huh?
Huh? Wha...?!
Hey, I looked all over for you guys!
Zoro! You too?!
What're you doing there?
That's my line, moron!
{Well, Marine guys kept saying,
"go north," "go north,"-OG}Well, the Marines kept
telling me to go north,
so I came up here!
{"North" and "up" are totally
different, you know!-OG}"North" and "up" are totally
different, dumbass!
Well in any case, nice work!
{Go up from there
and destroy the clock tower!-OG}Keep heading up
and trash that clock tower!
They can't!
What?!
{They can't go inside the clock tower
from where they are.-OG}The tower is inaccessible
from their current location.
{Other than entering
from the sky, the only way up is the stairs in the back
on the first floor.-OG}Unless you're flying, the only way in
is a staircase at the back of the first floor.
{But Zoro can destroy
the tower wall and...-OG}But Zoro could just smash
through the tower walls...
{We don't know if the cannonball
can bear that kind of shock!-OG}The cannonball might
explode from the shock!
{We have no choice but
to go up the stairs after all!-OG}We'll have to climb the stairs after all!
Wait, Vivi!
What?
I've got an idea!
Ribbit... ribbit, ribbit, ribbit...
Hey listen, Mr. 7.
This will be our final mission.
Ribbit, ribbit, ribbit...
Mr. 7
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
Mr. 7
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
Mr. 7
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
Ms. Father's Day
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
Ms. Father's Day
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
Ms. Father's Day
Frontier Agent
Baroque Works
That's the plan.
According to the plan,
we have thirty seconds left.
Who are they?!
Mr. 7 and Miss Father's Day!